Hello everyone welcome to Grow
with Shubham.  Friends, if you are also
preparing for IC38 exam, then
this video is for you.  You should
stay till the end of this video and by
watching this video
you can clear your exam in the first attempt itself.
All these questions are most important
which come again and again in the exam.  So
let's see what are our most
important questions and answers.
See, our first question comes in which
year Insurance Act was passed in India?
In which year was the Insurance Act passed in India?  Our first option is
1680, B option is 1938,
C option is 205 and D option is 1999.  So
see, our answer to this question is that our
Insurance Act was
passed in India in 1938.  Let's see the
next question, our question number two.
Reasons for Surrender of the Policy.  In
which reason can a policy holder surrender his policy
?  So, we have four
options for this.  The first option is advisor
induced.  The second option is has
financial problems and the third option
is no commission and the third option is es.  That means something is
assured.  So, the main
reason for us, the policy holder who
surrenders the policy, the main reason for
us is that he has financial problems.
Due to financial problems,
our policy holder
surrenders the policy.  So let's come to our next
question.  Our next question
is Ram Buys a Policy on the Life of
Suman.  Who is Ram?  Ram has bought a policy on Suman's life.
So who is Ram?  The ah so this is
our four options.  The first
option is life assured.  The Second Option Is
Appoint Team.  The third option is nominee and the
D option is proposer.  So according to this you
can see that according to what we have asked,
our Ram can be our
proposal.  So the right answer is D
proposition.
So let's look at the next question.
Insurance Agent Represents The You see, the
IC38 exam you are giving is the
insurance agent exam.
So what does an insurance agent
represent?  Insurance
company as a broker to agent sub agent.  So
our answer is that the insurance agent
represents our insurance company.
He represents the company from which he takes the policy.
The next is insurance benefits.
What does insurance benefit entail?  Who
is our insurance benefit for?  Our insurance provides benefits for the society, for the
country,
for individuals, for all of the above or for everyone.
So our
answer is ours as individuals.
Option C is the correct answer.  The insurance
benefits we provide are only to individuals.
He provides our benefits to the policy holder who buys the insurance.
Ok?  Then
next is DASH is the maximum limit of
liability of the insured under the policy.  What
is our maximum limit of liability
for the insured under the policy?
The fourth option is the first one is some
insured.  The second option is premium.  The
third option is the surrender value and the fourth
option is the amount of loss.  The correct answer is
some insured.  Sum Insured is our maximum
limit of liability under the policy of the insured.
The next question is what does not go on
to make a healthy relationship?  Which of these
options does not constitute a healthy relationship
?  The Four are our four options
given to us.  The first one is attraction, the
second option is trust.  The third option is
communication and the fourth option is
capitalism.  So see, our answer to this is that
it creates a healthy relationship for us.
Attraction also
creates a healthy relationship.  Trust also
creates a healthy relationship.
Communication also creates a healthy relationship.
So our last option is
skepticism which does
not create a healthy relationship.  So our
answer is skepticism.  Look, let
me tell you the meaning of skepticism.
That capitalism means
distrust.
Ok?  Let's next question is which among the
following is a method of risk transfer?
Look, the questions I will show you
now are three to four questions whose
answers are mostly the same.  But the
question to be asked is different.  But this is the
most important question.  Our question on this topic is
definitely asked in all the exams.
Which among the following is a method of
risk transfer?  Which is our method of risk transfer? Out of all
these, Bank FD, No
Insurance, Equity Shares, Real Estate, so
your answer is Insurance,
Insurance is our risk transfer, so
which is our method of risk transfer?
Insurance is the method of risk
transfer,
okay now let's see the next question, the
next question is the same, that means the answer is the same,
but our method of asking is
different.  See, he has asked,
Insurance is a process of
whose process is insurance?  Our four options are given.
Risk Transfer, Insured,
Financial Loss, Risk Retention.  As
you have just seen in our previous question,
insurance is a process of
risk transfer.  Insurance is
a process of transferring our risk.  Ok?  Now
you look at the next question.  Now
our next question is, risk transfer through
risk pulling is called, what do we call our risk
transfer through risk pulling
?  You will see that all three
questions are similar.  All three answers are same,
similar.  But the questions
asked are a little different.  The
way of asking is different.
But these are among the most important questions.
We have four options given
in this question.  The first one is saving.  The second
option is investment.  The third option is
insurance and the fourth option is risk
mitigation.  The answer is insurance.
What is our insurance?  Risk transfer
through risk pooling is called insurance.
Ok?  So let's see the next one.  Dash Is
Not An Indicator Of Service Quality.
Which of the following is not an indicator of service quality
?  Our four options are
given like this.  Cleverness, Reliability,
Empathy, Responsiveness.
The Answer Is Cleverness.  Cleverness is not an
indicator of service quality.
Next comes The Redressal of Public
Grievances Rules.  When was your redressal, the
Public Grievances Rules, made?  We had it
in 1998.  You are given four options.  The First
Option is 1996, the B Option is 1997, the Third
Option is 1998, the D Option is 1999.  The
correct answer is 1998.  The Redressal of
Public Grievances Rules in 1998.
The Next Is Premium Cannot Be
Received.  The premium that the policy holder pays to us
, the premium that he pays to the insurance company
, in which form is it
not received?  The option is four.  The
first option is in cash.  In cash, your
premium is received by cheque.
Our premium is also received through cheque.   The
premium of the policy holder is received
from the insurance company by
promissory note.  This is the answer.  Our
premium has been received.  It is
not our receipt through our promissory note.  The
Answer Is By Promissory Note.
The Next Is IGMS Stands For.
See, there is a full form of Mostant.
Any full form can be yours.  The question
asked right now is what IGMS
stands for.  We have given four options.
International Grievance Management System.  B has
provided Integrated Grievance Management
System.  The B option is correct.
Integrated Grievance Management System is
stands for IGMS stands for
Integrated Grievance Management System.
Ok.  The next is risk indicators.
What does risk indicate?  Fear of the
unknown.  Chance of loss.  Disturbances at
public places hazard.  The answer is chance of
loss.  The risk indicates our chance of loss.
Next is Dash is not a tangible good.
You have been given four options.
You definitely have a question about tangible goods.  This is
1000% your question on Tangible.  Out
of these, you have to tell which
tangible good is not yours.  House,
insurance, mobile phone, pair of jeans.  You
can see that among these, our house is
also a tangible good.  Mobile phone is also a tangible
good.  A pair of jeans is also our tangible
good.  So we have only one insurance which is
not our tangible good.  So our
answer to this question is that
option B is correct.  Insurance.
Next is insurance policy is a dash
contract.  Which
contract is an insurance policy?  Our four options are given.
Risk, Legal, Consent, Non-Legal.
Now tell me which is the answer in this?  See,
our answer to this is legal.
Insurance policy is a legal contract.
Insurance policy is our legal
contract.
Now let us look at the next question.  Dash
has jurisdiction to entertain matters where the
value of goods and services and the compensation
claim is up to 20 lakhs.  Which is that
jurisdiction where the value of your
goods and services, which is the matter,
our compensation claim can be
up to 20 lakhs,
in which jurisdiction can your claim be made,
we have been given four options, High Court,
District Forum, State Commission, National Commission,
so our matter which is up to 20 lakhs, is
solved in our District Forum.
The next one is has jurisdiction to entertain matters where
value of goods and services
and the compensation claim is above.  Now you have the
same question in this question.  Just a little
difference was done in this.
In our District Forum, cases up to Rs 20 lakh were
solved.  Whatever
matter there was, it was solved.  Now
he has asked that in which jurisdiction do our cases of above Rs 20 lakh and
below Rs 1 crore occur
?  Our four option beans are given in this.
High Court, District Forum, State
Commission, National Commission.  So, your matters ranging from Rs 20 lakh to
above and below Rs 1 crore are
solved through the State Commission.  Look, the question which I have
told you is the previous
question and this question now comes, our
next question comes which is
on the same basis.  You see, Dash has
jurisdiction to entertain matters with value
of goods and services and the compensation
claim is above Rs 1 crore.  I want to tell you which
jurisdiction is there, our matter, the
value of goods and services worth Rs 1
crore, is solved there.
Our four options are High Court,
District Forum, State Commission, National
Commission.  Now you saw that our three questions are same with
slight differences.
Our one is below 20 lakhs, above 20
lakhs, below 1 crore and the third one is above
1 crore.  These three questions are very
important questions.  One of these
questions is definitely asked of you.  So you have to
set these three points in your mind
that which form of yours and which
commission solves this matter for you.
Matters of what value does it solve?
So see, this is the last question of our video.
Dash has jurisdiction to entertain
matters value of goods and services and the
compensation claim is above Rs 1 crore.  Our
options are High Court, District Forum,
State Commission, National Commission.  Friends, this
question you have is for all of you.
Please tell us your answer by commenting
and if you liked our video then
please share it as much as possible, like it
and do not forget to subscribe to our channel.  We will keep
bringing end answers in this manner.
So stay till the end and
keep watching and do not forget to comment the answers to this question.